Well,
cue-2
good day to you. William Hogarth at your
service, painter and engraver. Some would
cue-3
say satirist too. Some, if you'll pardon
me for saying so, have said
cue-4
genius, but I know no such thing as
genius. Genius is nothing but
cue-5
labor and diligence. And so you find me
here,
cue-6
laboring once more at a new set of
pictures. My subject? Why, one of the
cue-7
most contentious, chaotic, and corrupt
spectacles to be seen in these British
cue-8
Isles during the reign of our sovereign
George II, an election for Parliament.
cue-9
Why should I want to capture on canvas
such a farcical phenomenon?
cue-10
Well, talk of this year's general election
is still fresh on everyone's
cue-11
lips. Yea, 1754 will go down as the most
absurd of
cue-12
political contests. At Oxfordshire, they
say 40,000 pounds was
cue-13
spent, and even then, no clear result.
cue-14
If I can show this preposterousness in
paint, it's sure to sell. My four canvases
cue-15
first, then the engravings I'll make from
them.
cue-16
People like a story, and that's what I'll
give 'em,
cue-17
the story of an election in four scenes,
from the start of the campaign to the
cue-18
victory parade. And I'll show it all, a
system built on bribery and
cue-19
bullying, self-interest and sleaze, but
also the great carnival that our
cue-20
constitution sets going every time there's
a contest. Few can vote, but
cue-21
everyone can take part. Come, let me show
you my paintings. Each
cue-22
has a thousand details, comical, strange,
and scandalous.
cue-23
I satirize the politics of 18th century
England, but perhaps they're not so
cue-24
different from your own.